Guide to the Natalie L. M. Petesch Papers, 1940-2006 SC.2006.01
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Manuscripts and Related Materials, 1940-2005; I.
  - The Immigrant Train and Other Stories, 1970-1996; 2.
    - Archetype of "Stasio" with Corrected Pages (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Fowle Papers for "Sisters"/"Immigrant Train", 1995 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Fowle Papers for "Pawel in America" (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Archetype of "The Way We Lived Then" (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Fowle Papers for "The Way We Lived Then", 1995 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Fowle Papers for "Orphan Train" (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Fowle Papers for "Witold Dobrzynski"/"God's Place" (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Notes for "The Way We Lived Then" (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Fowle Papers for "Czesio", 1993 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Fowle Papers for "Cirikwo: A Gypsy's Tale" (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Archetype of "The Orphan Train" (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Archetype and Corrected Typed Copy of "The Way We Lived Then" (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Fowle Papers for "Newt Newsie/"Stasio"/"Immigrant Train" (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Fowle Papers - Review of What We Save for Last by Corinne Bliss, 1992 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Fowle Papers for "Stefan Zarenski"/"The Beekeeper", 1994 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Final Revisions to Flowering Mimosa, 1986 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Archetype of "Stefan Zarenski"/"The Beekeeper" (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Archetype (copy) of "Stasio", 1993 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Archetype of "Czesio: Lawrence, Mass. 1912" (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Archetype of "God's Place" (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Corrected Final Copy of "Cousin Ludwika" (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Archetype of "Cousin Ludwika" (Box 17, Folder 14)
    - Archetype of "Cirikwo: A Gypsy's Tale" (Box 17, Folder 15)
    - "Cirikwo: A Gypsy's Tale" (Box 17, Folder 16)
    - Notes on "Pawel" for Train (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - Justina of Andalusia and Other Stories, 1986-1990; 3.
    - Various Drafts of "At Alberto's Bar" (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Copies of "Flowers for Emilio" (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - "The Divine Michaelangelo" (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - "Another Eden" (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - "Original II" of Justina of Andalusia (reference copy), 1989 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Page-Proofed Manuscript of Justina of Andalusia, 1989 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - "Manolo's Secret" as Appearing in New Letters with Notes (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - "Senor Coloma's Class" (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Outline of Another Eden (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - "The Future of Ramiro Caballero" (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - "Traveling with Felipe" (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Acknowledgments for Justina (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - Revised Version of Justina, 1989 (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - "Dionisio's Restaurant" (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - Galleys for Justina (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Short Version of "Lucky Manolo" (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Original Long Version of "Lucky Manolo" (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - "Opening Day" (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Copy Edited Version of Justina of Andalusia, 1990 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Maps of Monterrey (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Clippings on Mexico and AIDS, c. 1986 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Original Typescript of Another Eden Before it Became Justina (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - Letters re:Justina in Contests, 1989 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Copy of Another Eden as Rejected by an Agent (1/2) (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Copy of Another Eden as Rejected by an Agent (2/2) (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Various Long-Form Works, 1946-1990; 4.
    - Dissertation Abstract, 1962 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Dissertation Archetype (1/2), 1962 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Dissertation Archetype (2/2), 1962 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Chapter Omitted from Dissertation (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Ceremony of Innocence: A Study of Narrative Techniques in Henry James (Doctoral Dissertation - Undated Draft with Notes), Part I, Chapters I-V (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Ceremony of Innocence: A Study of Narrative Techniques in Henry James (Doctoral Dissertation - Undated Draft with Notes), Part II, Chapters VI-X (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Ceremony of Innocence: A Study of Narrative Techniques in Henry James (Doctoral Dissertation - Final Copy), Part I, Chapters I-VI, June 1962 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Ceremony of Innocence: A Study of Narrative Techniques in Henry James (Doctoral Dissertation - Final Copy), Part II, Chapters VII-X, June 1962 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - After the First Death There Is No Other (1/3) (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - After the First Death There Is No Other (2/3) (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - After the First Death There Is No Other (3/3) (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - "The Girl Who Was Afraid of Snow" (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Galley Proofs of Duncan's Colony (1/3), 1981 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Galley Proofs of Duncan's Colony (2/3), 1981 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Galley Proofs of Duncan's Colony (3/3), 1981 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Source Material from Carlos Wilson Used for "Carillo" Section of Duncan's Colony, 1974-1975 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - The Eringtons: A Novel of Three Sisters (a.k.a. The Soul Divided) (1/4), 1948-1950 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - The Eringtons: A Novel of Three Sisters (a.k.a. The Soul Divided) (2/4), 1948-1950 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - The Eringtons: A Novel of Three Sisters (a.k.a. The Soul Divided) (3/4), 1948-1950 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - The Eringtons: A Novel of Three Sisters (a.k.a. The Soul Divided) (4/4), 1948-1950 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Notes for The Eringtons/Souls Divided, 1948 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Flesh of My Flesh (1/2), ca. 1950 (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Flesh of My Flesh (2/2), ca. 1950 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Flowering Mimosa Original (1/3) (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Flowering Mimosa Original (2/3) (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Flowering Mimosa Original (3/3) (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Maps and Photos from Idaho (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Clippings for Flowering Mimosa, 1982-1984 (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Research Materials for Flowering Mimosa (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Very First Rough Draft of "Julia" Section (pp.88-169) (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - Final Chapter (approx. pp. 308-330) (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - Notes on Research Sources for Flowering Mimosa (Box 24, Folder 10)
    - Spiral Notebooks re: Flowering Mimosa, 1982 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Idaho Notes for "Pillars of Ore" (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous Research Material for Flowering Mimosa (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Idaho (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - A Few Bizarre Articles on Idaho (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Bunker Hill Materials (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Some Idaho Biblio (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - Complete Original Manuscript of Going Into the War (1/3) (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - Complete Original Manuscript of Going Into the War (2/3) (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Complete Original Manuscript of Going Into the War (3/3) (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Selections from Going Into the War Published in Anthologies (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Complete Manuscript of Going Into the War (1/2) (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Complete Manuscript of Going Into the War (2/2) (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - Unexpurgated Copy of The Grievance Adjustor (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Xerox of "The Vita-Brothel," Chapter Removed from The Grievance Adjustor, 1973-1974 (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - Contract for French Translation of Grievance Adjustor, 1979 (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - Copy of The Grievance Adjustor as Sent to Spain for Translation (1/2), 1990 (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - Copy of The Grievance Adjustor as Sent to Spain for Translation (2/2), 1990 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - The Odyssey of Katinou Kalokovich Galley Sheets and Corrections (1/2), 1979 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - The Odyssey of Katinou Kalokovich Galley Sheets and Corrections (2/2), 1979 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Outline for The Odyssey of Katinou Kalokovich, 1972-1973 (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Original Long Version of The Long Hot Summers of Yasha K/Seasons Such as These (1/5), 1967 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Original Long Version of The Long Hot Summers of Yasha K/Seasons Such as These (2/5), 1967 (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Original Long Version of The Long Hot Summers of Yasha K/Seasons Such as These (3/5), 1967 (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Original Long Version of The Long Hot Summers of Yasha K/Seasons Such as These (4/5), 1967 (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - Original Long Version of The Long Hot Summers of Yasha K/Seasons Such as These (5/5), 1967 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Perfect Original Copy of The Long Hot Summers of Yasha K (1/2), 1971-1972 (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Perfect Original Copy of The Long Hot Summers of Yasha K (2/2), 1971-1972 (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Material from Mississippi for Seasons Such as These (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Outline of Seasons Such as These, 1967 (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - List of Letters of Inquiry Sent re: Seasons Such as These, ca. 1967 (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - Original Copy of Tree Without Wings (1/2), 1946 (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - Original Copy of Tree Without Wings (2/2), 1946 (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - Revisions to Tree Without Wings (1/2), 1946 (Box 28, Folder 9)
    - Revisions to Tree Without Wings (2/2), 1946 (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Corrected Galley Proofs of Wild With All Regret (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Galleys of Wild With All Regret (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - "The Street," "Benito in Love," and "Through a Glass, Darkly" (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - "Benito in Love" (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - "Cheaper Potatoes" (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - "Heroes" (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - Notes and Revisions for "I, Constanza" (Box 29, Folder 8)
    - "I, Constanza", 1980 (Box 29, Folder 9)
    - "I, Constanza" (Box 29, Folder 10)
    - "The Life and Letters of Hannah Gordon" (Box 29, Folder 11)
    - "A Man Called Manuel" (Box 29, Folder 12)
    - "A Man Called Manuel" as Accepted by Crazyhorse, 1984 (Box 29, Folder 13)
    - "Through a Glass, Darkly" (Box 29, Folder 14)
    - "Through a Glass, Darkly" (Box 29, Folder 15)
    - "Zhenia and the Wicked One" (Box 29, Folder 16)
    - "Zhenia and the Wicked One" (Box 29, Folder 17)
    - Writ in Remembrance (1/3), 1952-1958 (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - Writ in Remembrance (2/3), 1952-1958 (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - Writ in Remembrance (3/3), 1952-1958 (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - Complete Manuscript of Writ in Remembrance (1/3), 1952-1958 (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - Complete Manuscript of Writ in Remembrance (2/3), 1952-1958 (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - Complete Manuscript of Writ in Remembrance (3/3), 1952-1958 (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - Short Story Excerpted from Writ in Remembrance, 1957 (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Various Short Works, 1940-1998; 5.
    - "The Anesthetist" (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - "Alaric and I", 1967 (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - "All Texans are Seven Feet Tall with Some Exceptions", 1965 (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - "Anything New Under the Sun?" (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - "The Assassins" (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - "Be Not Forgetful of Strangers", 1976 (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - "The Boy", ca. 1985 (Box 31, Folder 7)
    - "By the Sweat of Your Brow" (Box 31, Folder 8)
    - "The Catechumen", ca. 1948 (Box 31, Folder 9)
    - "Corinna", 1967 (Box 31, Folder 10)
    - "Dancing" (Box 31, Folder 11)
    - "Dancing" as Appearing in New Letters (Box 31, Folder 12)
    - "Doing It Like Velasquez" (Box 31, Folder 13)
    - "The Emporers of Ice Cream" (Box 31, Folder 14)
    - "Ericka" (Box 31, Folder 15)
    - "The Exile" (Box 31, Folder 16)
    - "The Exile" (offprint) (Box 31, Folder 17)
    - "A Few Words About Texas" for South Dakota Review, 1975 (Box 31, Folder 18)
    - "Filled With Eternity", 1949-1950 (Box 31, Folder 19)
    - "The Glassmakers" (Box 31, Folder 20)
    - "The Glassmakers" (Box 31, Folder 21)
    - "A Golem's Tale: How Shari Goldman and I Brought Joy to the World" (Box 31, Folder 22)
    - "The Great Michael Macauley", 1949-1950 (Box 31, Folder 23)
    - "A Greeting Card for Immigrants", ca. 1998 (Box 31, Folder 24)
    - "How I Lost the War in Texas", ca. 1965 (Box 31, Folder 25)
    - "In America Begin Responsibilities" (Box 31, Folder 26)
    - "Jessup County Justice", 1948-1950 (Box 31, Folder 27)
    - "A Journal for the New Year" (Box 31, Folder 28)
    - "Joy to the World" Published as "A Golem's Tale", 1975 (Box 31, Folder 29)
    - "The Laugh", ca. 1980s (Box 31, Folder 30)
    - "The Laughter of Hastings Street: An Autobiographical Memoir" from the Gale Contemporary Authors Autobiography Series (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - "The Laughter of Hastings Street", 1990 (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - "Learning to Breathe in the Age of Aquarius" (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - "Losses" (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - "Losses" (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - "Love", 1983 (Box 32, Folder 6)
    - "A Love Letter to Peter Dalosso" (Box 32, Folder 7)
    - "Lovers' Reunions in the Year 2000" (Box 32, Folder 8)
    - "Lunching with Tenney" (Box 32, Folder 9)
    - "Main Street Morning" (Box 32, Folder 10)
    - "Main Street Morning" (offprint), 1978 (Box 32, Folder 11)
    - "Malini's Bride" (Box 32, Folder 12)
    - Clippings that Inspired "Malini's Bride", 1991-1992 (Box 32, Folder 13)
    - Fowle Papers for "Malini's Bride", 1992 (Box 32, Folder 14)
    - "A Man of Intellect", 1949-1950 (Box 32, Folder 15)
    - Short Version of "A Manual for the Corridors" as Returned from Indiana Review Contest (Box 32, Folder 16)
    - Editorial Notes on "A Manual for the Corridors" from David Bourne of Artful Dodge, 1997 (Box 32, Folder 17)
    - Long Version of "A Manual for the Corridors" (Box 32, Folder 18)
    - Handwritten Manuscript of "A Manual for the Corridors" (Box 32, Folder 19)
    - Revisions to "A Manual for the Corridors" for NEA Grant Application, 1992 (Box 32, Folder 20)
    - Fowle Papers for "A Manual for the Corridors", 1992 (Box 32, Folder 21)
    - "Minerva at the Peace Corps", 1963-1966 (Box 32, Folder 22)
    - "My Future" (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - "The Myth of the Monster Mother-in-Law," Excerpted from Going Into the War (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - "The Nightingale", 1948-1949 (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - "No Such Thing as Death" (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - "No Such Thing as Death" (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - "Of Love and Art: A Tale of Paradoxes", 1991 (Box 33, Folder 6)
    - "The Parrot", ca. 1966 (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - "The Parting", 1948 (Box 33, Folder 8)
    - "Pillars of Love", 1985 (Box 33, Folder 9)
    - "The Poet and the Penny", 1947-1948 (Box 33, Folder 10)
    - "A Race Riot Recollected in Tranquility" (Box 33, Folder 11)
    - "Running" ("Short-Story" Story), 1982 (Box 33, Folder 12)
    - "Shopping", 1978 (Box 33, Folder 13)
    - "Socking It Away" (Box 33, Folder 14)
    - "The Street" (Box 33, Folder 15)
    - "Sunday Evening" (Box 33, Folder 16)
    - "Thomas" (Box 33, Folder 17)
    - "The Truth" in The University Review 31.4, June 1965 (Box 33, Folder 18)
    - "The Truth", 1964 (Box 33, Folder 19)
    - "Up-Tight With Swami Ramananda", 1960s (Box 33, Folder 20)
    - "Who Am I To Speak?", 1997 (Box 33, Folder 21)
    - "A Woman with a Soul", 1953 (Box 33, Folder 22)
    - "A Writer in the Mechanical Age", 1946-1947 (Box 33, Folder 23)
    - Pennsylvania Stories Submitted for an Anthology, 1984 (Box 33, Folder 24)
    - College Literary Magazines Containing Published Poems, 1954-1955 (Box 33, Folder 25)
    - Poems Written in High School and College, 1940-1956 (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - Extra Copies of Stories Appearing in Various Collections (1/2) (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - Extra Copies of Stories Appearing in Various Collections (2/2) (Box 34, Folder 3)
- Notebooks, 1964-1986; II.
  The notebooks in this series are mostly spiral-bound stenographic notebooks that Petesch used for a variety of purposes throughout her writing life. Many are numbered, and it appears that she carried these in her daily life to write down miscellaneous thoughts and inspirations. Though the sequencing is inconsistent, an effort has been made to arrange these notebooks in chronological order. Petesch dedicated other volumes to brainstorming or research for a particular project, or brought them on trips to record her observations. Many of the notebooks served a dual function as scrapbooks, where Petesch curated newspaper clippings relevant to a topic or time in her life. In these materials researchers can expect to find a unique snapshot of the author's mind at work as she moved through the world with the eyes of a writer.
  - Notebook #15 (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - Notebook for The Long Hot Summers of Yasha K (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - Notebook on Florida Flora and Fauna (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - Notebook #7, Alabama (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - Notebook #8, The Odyssey of Katinou Kalokovich (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - Notebook on Women for The Odyssey of Katinou Kalokovich (Box 34, Folder 9)
  - Notes for The Odyssey of Katinou Kalokovich (Box 34, Folder 10)
  - Notebooks #1-3, 1964 (Box 34, Folder 11)
  - Notebook #4, 1965 (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - Notebook #6, Clippings on Alabama and Texas, 1966 (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - Notebooks #4-5, 1966-1967 (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - Notebooks #6-7, 1967-1969 (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - Notebook #8, 1970 (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - Notebook from Baltimore, 1973 (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - Notebook for The Grievance Adjustor, 1973 (Box 35, Folder 7)
  - Notebook #9, 1974-1975 (Box 35, Folder 8)
  - Notebook #10, 1975-1976 (Box 35, Folder 9)
  - Notebook, 1976 (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Spanish Notebook, 1976-1977 (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - Spanish Notebooks, 1977 (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - Spanish Notebook #14, 1977 (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - Notebook, 1977 (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - Notebook #15, 1977 (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - Notebook, 1978 (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - Notebook, 1978 (Box 36, Folder 8)
  - Notebook #13, 1978-1979 (Box 36, Folder 9)
  - Notebook, 1979 (Box 36, Folder 10)
  - Notebook #14, 1979 (Box 36, Folder 11)
  - French Notebook, 1979-1980 (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Notebook #16, Going Into the War, 1980 (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - Notebook #17, 1980 (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - Notebook, 1980-1981 (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - Spanish Vocabulary, 1980-1981 (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - Notebook, 1981 (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - Spanish Notebook, 1981 (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - Notebook, 1982 (Box 37, Folder 8)
  - Notebook, Before and After Spain, 1983 (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Notebook, 1983-1984 (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - Notebook on George Meredith's Letters, 1984 (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - Notebook, 1984 (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - Notebook, 1984-1985 (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - Spanish Vocabulary, 1984-1985 (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - Notebook, 1985-1986 (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - Notebook from Monterrey, 1986 (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - Spain, 1986 (Box 38, Folder 9)
  - Notebook from Monterrey, Mexico, 1987 (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - Final Pages of Duncan's Colony (Xeroxed Clippings) (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - Brochure from the Minnie Stevens Piper Foundation, 1962-1963 (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - Notebook Documenting Publication Efforts for Short Stories and Novels (Box 39, Folder 4)
- Correspondence, 1947-2006; III.
  Petesch corresponded with a wide variety of friends and family, as well as publishers, agents, and fellow authors, especially from the 1970s through the 1990s when her career was at its most prolific. The items in this series mainly consist of copies of Petesch's outgoing letters, which she retained for her files. Of particular note is her extensive correspondence with her daughter, Rachel Maines, beginning around the time of her divorce in 1960 and continuing up until the donation of the collection in 2006. Petesch also correspondend significantly with friend and author David Ray.
  Upon the donation of the collection, much of the correspondence, particularly with friends and family, was in miscellaneous files with approximate and overlapping date ranges; due to the volume of these materials, this arrangement has been maintained. Correspondence that was significant enough for Petesch to designate by specific correspondent in her files appears in Subseries 1. and 2., arranged alphabetically where possible. The more miscellaneous materials appear in Subseries 3. Miscellaneous and Subject-Based Correspondence.
  - Individual Correspondents, 1962-2006; 1.
    - Ayala, Juan, 1981 (Box 39, Folder 5)
    - Barnes, Jane, 1977-1979 (Box 39, Folder 6)
    - Barnes, Jim (Chariton Review), 1985-2004 (Box 39, Folder 7)
    - Berjeron, Aline, 1962-1968 (Box 39, Folder 8)
    - Berroa, Rei and Sarah, 1981-1989 (Box 39, Folder 9)
    - Bethel, Gar, 1994-2005 (Box 39, Folder 10)
    - Bliss Corinne, 1978-1991 (Box 39, Folder 11)
    - Bonnetti, Kay (American Audio Library), 1982-1983 (Box 39, Folder 12)
    - Bruchac, Joe and Carol (Greenfield Review), 1980-1985 (Box 39, Folder 13)
    - Brutus, Dennis (University of Pittsburgh), 1989-1990 (Box 39, Folder 14)
    - Bukoski, Anthony ("Tony"), 1997-2006 (Box 39, Folder 15)
    - Carnahan, Peter (Pennsylvania Council for the Arts), 1979-1992 (Box 39, Folder 16)
    - Clifton, Merritt, 1979-1980 (Box 39, Folder 17)
    - Cohen, Lynne, 1980-1981 (Box 39, Folder 18)
    - Colter, Cyrus, 1978 (Box 39, Folder 19)
    - Correnti, Frank (Pittsburgh Quarterly), 1997-1998 (Box 39, Folder 20)
    - Cunningham, Michael, 1978 (Box 39, Folder 21)
    - Dahm, Eva, 1978 (Box 39, Folder 22)
    - Daire-Reber, Ginger (United Sisters), 1978-1979 (Box 39, Folder 23)
    - DeStefano, Chris, 1981 (Box 39, Folder 24)
    - Driskell, Leon and Sue, 1976-1985 (Box 39, Folder 25)
    - Dove, Rita and Fred, 1980-2000 (Box 39, Folder 26)
    - Fabre, Michel, 1980-1983 (Box 39, Folder 27)
    - Fenton, Lu, 1980-1982 (Box 39, Folder 28)
    - Ferrarelli, Rina, 1999-2005 (Box 39, Folder 29)
    - Fox, Bob (Carpenter Press, Ohio University Press), 1980-1981 (Box 39, Folder 30)
    - Gass, William, 1976 (Box 39, Folder 31)
    - Gilbert, Richard (Ohio University Press), 2004 (Box 39, Folder 32)
    - Groffsky, Maxine (Literary Agent), 1979 (Box 39, Folder 33)
    - Gutkind, Lee (Creative Nonfiction), 1997-1999 (Box 39, Folder 34)
    - Guy, Bill, 2005 (Box 39, Folder 35)
    - Healy, Lisa (Doubleday), 1979 (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - Helfand, Mike and Janet, 1981 (Box 40, Folder 2)
    - Johanos, Eve, 1978 (Box 40, Folder 3)
    - Klein, Jeffrey (New Dimensions), 1975 (Box 40, Folder 4)
    - Kozer, Jose, 1990 (Box 40, Folder 5)
    - Lammon, Martin ("Marty"), 1980-1981 (Box 40, Folder 6)
    - Lieberman, Larry, 1980 (Box 40, Folder 7)
    - Lindberg, Stanley (Georgia Review), 1979-1980 (Box 40, Folder 8)
    - Lusk, Daniel (National Public Radio), 1979-1980 (Box 40, Folder 9)
    - Macaya, Isabel Diaz (1/2), 2000-2006 (Box 40, Folder 10)
    - Macaya, Isabel Diaz (2/2), 2000-2006 (Box 40, Folder 11)
    - Photos and Negatives from Trip to San Carlos Hospital Clinicio with Isabel Diaz Macaya, 2000 (Box 40, Folder 12)
    - Photos of Bombed Hospital During Spanish Civil War Sent by Isabel Diaz Macaya (Box 40, Folder 13)
    - Maines, Rachel (Daughter), 1960-1969 (Box 40, Folder 14)
    - Maines, Rachel (Daughter), 1970-1986 (Box 40, Folder 15)
    - Maines, Rachel (Daughter), 1987-1999 (Box 40, Folder 16)
    - Maines, Rachel (Daughter), 2000-2006 (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - Miner, Virginia, 1979 (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - Morrison, Toni, 1983 (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - Morrow, Daniel (HEART Magazine), 1997 (Box 41, Folder 4)
    - Munetic, Ann, 1979-1981 (Box 41, Folder 5)
    - Naslund, Sena, 1975-1976 (Box 41, Folder 6)
    - Nordan, Lewis ("Buddy"), 1997-2005 (Box 41, Folder 7)
    - Oates, Joyce Carol, 1974 (Box 41, Folder 8)
    - Osborne, Carolyn, 1978 (Box 41, Folder 9)
    - Petesch, Don, 1960s (Box 41, Folder 10)
    - Petrosky, Patti (Slow Loris Press), 1979-1980 (Box 41, Folder 11)
    - Pride, Anne (Motheroot Press), 1979-1985 (Box 41, Folder 12)
    - Proffer, Ellendea (ARDIS Publishers), 1976 (Box 41, Folder 13)
    - Rawson, Chris, 1994-1996 (Box 41, Folder 14)
    - Ray, David, 1978-2005 (Box 41, Folder 15)
    - The Old Klansman and Other Stories by David Ray, 1991 (Box 41, Folder 16)
    - Robinson, Ardelle, 1998-2001 (Box 41, Folder 17)
    - Rohrberger, Mary, 1998 (Box 41, Folder 18)